

Tiago Carreira DevOps Engineer

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- © +55 21 98303-3680
- ▼ tiago.g.carreira.br@gmail.com
- inkedin.com/in/tcarreira
- github.com/tcarreira

Soft Skills

- Productivity passionate
- Fast learner
- Highly adaptable
- Proactive and autonomous
- Good communicator
- Friendly and team player

Technical Skills

































Python

Monitoring

REST

Technological Values







Everything as code



Community driven

Personal Interests







Podcasts. Audiobooks

Activeness, Achievement

Learning, Improving

Languages

Portuguese



English



Spanish



French

Passionate about Linux, Open Source and productivity (I love scripting and automation). No person should be a single point of failure - procedures should be documented and/or automated. I'm looking towards working with **smart people**, with whom I could learn and help learning; where **autonomy** is a valuable asset and improving is more important than finding who made a mistake.

Having ~9 years of experience with DevOps, I'm experienced with modern technologies (eg: Docker), proficient with Linux systems and many DevOps tools (eg. git, CI/CD, monitoring) and I'm confident developing in Python and Go.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer @ Globo.com

Specialist (via Globo) - July 2021 - Present (8 months) Prio de Janeiro, Brazil Senior (via Stormgroup) - August 2020 - June (11 months) PRio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Designed / improved CI/CD Pipelines, using Gitlab-CI and Docker
- Improved reliability for an API Gateway (Kong), serving 10K requests/s
- Programed and patch different code stacks (bash, Go, python, Lua)
- Infrastructure deployment and automation at GCP with terraform

DevOps/Operations Engineer @ SAPO (BOLD by devoteam)

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Implemented a monitoring stack with High Availability, using Grafana + Prometheus + Thanos (solely)
- Developed a Python/Django RESTful API for SSL Cert management (solely from scratch to production)
- DevOps advocate: improving Continuous Integration and best practices among the organization
- Data Center migration: bare metal, VM's, networking, data and storage (ensuring no downtime)
- Maintaining 500+ servers (using Puppet), 100+ services, both legacy and modern systems, on-call 24/7
- Solving internal operational tickets: forensics, bugs detection, infrastructure management

DevOps Engineer @ Premium Minds

December 2013 - June 2017 (3 years 7 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Migrated on-premises infrastructure to AWS (EC2, RDS, VPC, ...)
- Infrastructure as code with python/boto3
- Defined the infrastructure and deployment pipeline for a High Available service on AWS telpark.com
- Managing Continuous Integration using Jenkins and Puppet

EDUCATION

MSc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Instituto Superior Técnico | 2007 - 2013 P Lisbon, Portugal

- Major / Minor: Robotics & Control Systems / Computers
- Principal subjects: Database management, Objects Oriented Programming, Robotics
- Thesis: Quadcopter/Drone Automatic Take Off / Landing on a (mobile) Docking Station

Associate Cloud Engineer

Google Cloud | Sep 2021

• <u>credential.net/c880f8ea-7724-4ad4-9ad9-cf3e3f79fc28</u>

Training & Courses

- May 2020 NDG Linux I/II course @ Cisco Networking Academy Essential System Services, Networking Fundamentals, Scripting, Administrative Tasks, Security
- Jan 2019 LPI DevOps Tools Engineer @ Linux Academy Config management, Cloud, RESTful APIs, Microservices, CI/CD, Security, Monitoring

OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

2022 - FOSDEM 2022: Ubuntu stand website design & support - stands.fosdem.org/stands/ubuntu

2021 - TreeTree2: computer architecture I - github.com/tcarreira/nand2tetris-autograder

2020 - Podcasting (host, audio editor, web developer, designer) - github.com/marmita-de-redon Dashboard website project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/roaw2020

2019 - Speaker @ Pyjamas Conf 2019 (Django on Docker) - github.com/tcarreira/django-docker Speaker @ Ubucon Europe 2019 (Docker) - tcarreira.github.io/presentations Volunteer (technical) @ Ubucon Europe 2019 - github.com/ubuconeurope

2018 - TreeTree2: HAC - Hacking the learn process on math/physics/programming with 10-16yo people

PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Sports: running (marathon), cycling (Lisbon-Santiago 600+ Km), obstacle course racing Music: clarinet, transverse flute, guitar, piano

Music groups: company's band, TUIST.tecnico.ulisboa.pt, multiple choirs, philharmonic orchestra Video production: youtube.carreira.pw, youtu.be/IKvtB-vNOek

Podcasting: marmita.pt (github.com/Marmita-de-Redon)

Personal skills: therapeutic massage (advanced integrated therapeutic massage course) Maker: Arduino, Raspberry Pi